# VENUGOPAL V CHAVATE

E-mail: venugopalchavate@gmail.com Phone: +91 9481814722

# **Professional Summary**

I have 4 years of experience in the IT industry. Currently, I am working on DevOps, Configuration Management, Build Management, Requirement Management, and Change Management by using licensed & other open-source tools. I am working on Gitlab Migration of applications where we migrate the existing structure of CI/CD to Gitlab Containerized Structure. On the server side, I am working on Windows and Linux.

# Work experience

#### ATMECS Technologies Pvt Ltd

July 2023 — Present

**Project**: Micro Services Architecture Migration

Role: Senior DevOps Engineer

About Client: Client is an R&D Group that is pioneering Hyperloop Transport Technology.

#### Responsibilities:

- I was responsible for creating a plan to transition the client's AI-based Application to containerized microservices from previously existing monolithic architecture using Docker.
- I was responsible for creating a robust deployment model using Docker-Compose on AWS
  EC2 instance using robust scripts for deployment and database backup.
- Enabled the developers to deploy or backup the database with a single command using created scripts.
- Provided detailed projection of the project cost and suggested client to optimize AWS resources to reduce costs.
- Provided insights to the client on their plans for Gitlab pipeline creation and Kubernetes Application.
- Helped client to save more than 1555 USD yearly and received appreciation from the client on the initiative and execution.

#### LTIMindtree LTD

June 2021 — May 2023

**Project**: Cloud Operations **Role**: Senior DevOps Engineer

About Client: Client is a Web service provider for Federal Governments of various countries.

#### Responsibilities:

- I automated the deployment cycle using Gitlab CI/CD. As Gitlab uses the Docker-IN-Docker (DinD) concept.
- I'm also responsible for the complete Migration of client-acquired product groups to Gitlab from various code bases such as Bit Bucket, Azure DevOps, Github, and SVN.
- Carried out Cloud operations on VPC peering to connect acquired accounts to private cloud,
  Terraform Changes.
- I have adequate knowledge of tools such as Chef, AWS ECS, AWS ECR, Postman, and Janus for the Deployment part.

This also required me to migrate the existing CI/CD structure to Gitlab. Thus I have adequate knowledge of CI/CD tools such as Jenkins, Teams City, Circle-CI, Travis, Octopus, and AppVeyor.

June 2015 — June 2019

**Project**: Development Support Team **Role**: IT Support – .NET DevOps

#### Responsibilities:

- I was working as a .NET Support Engineer.
- Worked on SCADA systems in client premises.
- I was to configure functionalities that required Jscript.NET, VB, and MSSQL scripting.
- I was also responsible for Chef-server check-ins.

### Qualifications

#### Certifications:

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Microsoft Azure Certified AZ900

#### Recognitions

Received Client recognition known as **Spot ON** Award from the client for consecutively 2 years for Expert Thinking and Client Satisfaction

## Skill Set

- Version Control Systems: Gitlab, Github, BitBucket, Azure DevOps, Tortoise SVN
- CI/CD Tools: Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins, Circle CI, TeamCity, AppVeyor, Travis CI
- Container Tools: Docker
- Container Storage Tools: Jfrog Artifactory, AWS S3, AWS ECR
- Deployment Tools: AWS ECS, Janus, Postman, Octopus.
- Configuration Management tools: Chef
- Cloud Operations: Terraform, VPC Peering Tasks, AWS Direct Connect
- Operating System: Microsoft Windows, Ubuntu, CentOS
- Language known: C#, YAML Scripting, Python
- Secret Management tools: AWS Secrets Manager
- Database known: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL

# Education

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E) SKSVMACET, Gadag, Karnataka, India

Branch: Electronics and Communication

12th Mar 2014 — Mar 2015

Chetan PU College, Hubli, Karnataka, India

Education Board: Department Of Pre-University Education

10th Mar 2012 — Mar 2013

Chetan Public School, Hubli, Karnataka, India

Education Board: Karnataka School and Assessment Board

# Interests